what I get a lot of the time from very
well-meaning people is that this has
been tried before and it's not worth it
it's not something that works and if
that was true I would put more stock
into it if we had actually tried
creating a maintaining technology
together there is no failure at this
because every time something goes wrong
we ask what went wrong and try to
improve it together and that's what
doesn't exist in all of these one-off
projects someone who created an
alternative to Facebook and it wasn't
successful of course it wasn't
successful you're competing with
Facebook the only way to compete with
Facebook is to do it together is to
create a social media tool we actually
want to use with ten thousand people a
hundred thousand people a million people
not a dozen people creating it and then
hoping they can market it and get you
entice you over from Facebook and then
the one offs that instagrams and the
snapchats are somewhat successful until
they're bought out by the by the big
companies and that is success the
individual projects I have talked about
I am bg4 politician a maybe Netflix of
apps all of these things have probably
been tried before and they haven't
succeeded but that wasn't us trying it
it wasn't us taking on risk collectively
it wasn't us solving the marketing and
funding problem one time so that every
new individual project gets to have
economies of scale and cost less and
less money as we move forward and have
more and more people come on board and
say what works for them and what doesn't
work for them every time a new
technology is made and then it fails we
have less trust in the new the next one
every time one comes on board and fails
we're like oh that was tried and it
didn't work no it has to be so perfect
to work that of course it didn't
we're not going to create perfect we're
going to create good enough and then
we're gonna keep improving it together
because it's ours it's not me selling
you something and it's an inferior
product it's ours what is the bare
minimum we need and then how do we keep
improving it and as far as I know that
has never been done before
cooperatives have been done before
cooperatives are powerful but a user
owned technology company that's here to
create all of
technology we need to live our
individual lives to create community to
create systems and platforms that help
make our lives better by empowering the
individual people to say what they need
and then employing people to create it
that has never been done before
that is the powerful piece creating it
together looking for what's working and
making more of it we look for what's not
working and making less of it improving
it creating diversity cuz technology
allows us to unlock diversity we don't
need branding our social media site
doesn't need to be Facebook it doesn't
need to be blue everywhere if you don't
like blue yours can be pink we don't
need to follow the same rules of game a
or capitalism we can create something
completely new we create the tools for
massive collaboration we have organized
cooperation which can easily out-compete
forced chaotic risky competition where
you have to be a unicorn to succeed we
don't have to be a unicorn we can start
out a cult
it grows start gluing horns on its head
itself just becomes a unicorn that's not
terrific let's not do that but like what
we can do together is more powerful less
risky and in that as far as I know this
has never been done before if it has
please link it below please set me up
with those people blockchain has tried
to do something similar to this but if
you don't have technology background if
you don't understand it they're like
don't worry we'll save the world on your
behalf
that's not the same this is anyone any
technology ability can come and be a
part of this you can come and see
transparently what is going on can come
and have a vote if they're a member in
good standing once we have the
capability to do that a better world is
on its way and we're allowing everyone
and anyone to participate voluntarily
thank you